Guide to the Hillhouse Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS, 1762-1931; Series XVI; 3.5 linear feet (9 boxes)
  - Papers of others
    - Whedon, Charles R.
      - Legal papers
        - William F. Cody v. William F. Carver, 1885 (Box 82, Folder 527)
        - Miscellanea, [ca. 1858-1886] (Box 83, Folder 528-533)
        - Miscellanea, [ca. 1858-1886] (Box 84, Folder 534-539)
        - Miscellanea, [ca. 1858-1886] (Box 85, Folder 540-545)
      - Papers: Democratic politics, 1853, 1868, undated (Box 86, Folder 546)
    - Whiting, Albertus D., and Henry Whitney: Bills and receipts, 1842-1855 (Box 86, Folder 547)
    - Woodbridge, Susan Augusta (Box 86, Folder 548)
      - Drawing, undated (Box 86, Folder 548)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified
    - Bills and receipts, 1840-1909, undated (Box 86, Folder 549)
    - Drawings: book of pencil sketches, "Water Cure", 1849 (Box 86, Folder 550)
    - Legal papers, [1648], undated (Box 86, Folder 551)
    - Notebooks: electrical terms, geometry, Italian grammar, undated (Box 86, Folder 552)
    - Notes and clippings: genealogies and obituaries
      - Hillhouse family, 1822-1931, undated (Box 86, Folder 553)
      - Lloyd family, 1884, undated (Box 86, Folder 554)
      - Other families, 1828-1914, undated (Box 86, Folder 555)
      - Writings
        - Descriptions of inventions, 1830, circa 1835 (Box 86, Folder 558)
        - Essays, 1886, undated (Box 86, Folder 558)
        - Poems, 1779-1853, undated (Box 86, Folder 558)
        - School exercises, undated (Box 86, Folder 559)
        - Sermons, 1762-1841 (Box 86, Folder 560)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 86, Folder 560)
    - Photographs, engravings, printed illustrations
      - People, Circa 1857-1920, undated (Box 86, Folder 556)
      - Buildings, coats-of-arms, miscellaneous, undated (Box 86, Folder 557)
    - Architectural drawings, 1828-1829, 1854, undated
      - Unidentified houses, by Alexander Jackson Davis and William Strickland; New York Central Railroad Waystation; Sachem's Wood (Box 87, Folder 561-564)
- OVERSIZE
  - Papers from his legal practice: insurance policies (including Hillhouse family policies), Circa 1837-1872 (Folder 88A)
  - Architectural drawings, contracts, and memoranda, mostly re: Sachem's Wood, many by Alexander Jackson Davis (1803-1892), 1829-1836, undated (Folder 88B)
  - Architectural drawings, mostly re: Sachem's Wood, including some by Davis, some by William Strickland (ca. 1787-1854), and probably some by Ithiel Town (1784-1844), 1828, undated (Folder 89A–89B)
  - Davis, Alexander Jackson, 1854, undated (Folder 89C–89E)
  - Architectural drawings, maps, and blueprints, mostly re: Sachem's Wood; also other New Haven locations; Pelham Manor, New York; Speyer's estate, Atlantic Highlands, New Jersey; and New York Central Railway, Circa 1841-1948 (Folder 89D)
  - Sachem's Wood blueprints (Box 90A–90C)
  - Profile map of unknown location; Museum of Exhibits from Peru; profile map of St. Ronan Street; map of Grove Street Cemetery and adjacent streets (Folder 91)
  - Sachem's Wood (Folder 92)